Guide to the David Daggett Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
David Daggett papers
1781-1851
MS 162
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7
(14 boxes)
Correspondence (primarily letters received) and other papers of David Daggett, Connecticut lawyer, jurist, politician, teacher, and author. The papers relate primarily to Daggett's legal and political activities and to Federalist Party politics. Important correspondents include Simeon Baldwin, Abraham Bishop, Isaac Bronson, John C. Calhoun, Henry Clay, Charles Denison, Elizur Goodrich, Gideon Granger, Roger Griswold, Rufus King, William Leffingwell, Josiah Meigs, Timothy Pickering, Benjamin Rush, John Cotton Smith, Daniel Webster, William Wirt, and Oliver Wolcott.
Daggett, David, 1764-1851
Existence and Location of Copies
Additional information not yet available in the online version of the finding aid exists in the repository. Contact Manuscripts and Archives for assistance.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Special Files.
Scope and Contents
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, consists primarily of letters received by Daggett, 1781-1848, many of which are of great interest because of the information they contain on politics and the practice of law.
There are substantial numbers of letters written to Daggett by his clients and other citizens consulting him on legal matters.
Daggett's political correspondence is extremely rich and revealing. He was a very active and powerful figure in the Connecticut Federalist Party and in Connecticut politics in general; and also, to the extent that his party and activities affected national affairs, a man of some prominence on the national political scene (cf. John Wood, Suppressed History of the Administration of John Adams, (1802), pp. 259-261 in J.H. Sherburne's 1968 edition).
Many letters of prominent Connecticut and national political figures are to be found throughout the correspondence. These letters are concerned with many of the important public issues of the time. Daggett's correspondents included Simeon Baldwin, Abraham Bishop, Isaac Bronson, John C. Calhoun, Henry Clay, Charles Denison, Elizur Goodrich, Gideon Granger, Roger Griswold, Rufus King, William Leffingwell, Josiah Meigs, Samuel F.B. Morse, Timothy Pickering, Benjamin Rush, Joseph Story, John Trumbull, Daniel Webster, Noah Webster, Eli Whitney, William Wirt, and Oliver Wolcott. For a complete list of correspondence, see the container list.
Special mention should be made of the approximately 150 letters that Daggett received from his old classmate and close friend at Yale, John Cotton Smith, a powerful politician and prominent public figure in his own right. Smith's letters, which span the years 1785-1844, are rich in trenchant comment and opinion on the political and social activities of early nineteenth-century United States.
Another important segment of the Daggett's correspondence is the approximately 120 letters that he wrote to his two daughters, Wealthy Ann (Daggett) Jenkins and Susan Edwards (Daggett) Dwight, and to his son, Leonard Augustus Daggett. This is the only substantial group of letters written by Daggett that the collection contains. These letters afford the best insights into Daggett's personality contained in the collection. They also contain additional information on political affairs and on his own career. There is also a substantial correspondence between Daggett and his personal attorney, William Bristol.
The correspondence has been arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Within the files under each name, letters have been arranged chronologically.
Series II, WRITINGS, consists of holograph drafts of essays, articles, pamphlets, lectures, and notes of these lectures taken by others. The items within the series have been arranged by type and a title listing will be found in the register.
Series III, SPECIAL FILES, consists of legal documents, business papers and account and day books, and a few clippings.
Biographical / Historical
David Daggett, Connecticut lawyer, politician, jurist, teacher, and author was born in Attleborough, Massachusetts on December 31, 1764, the sixth of nine children of Thomas and Sibulah (Stanley) Daggett.
After graduating from Yale in 1783, he supported himself by teaching in the Hopkins Grammar School, during which time he studied law under Charles Chauncey. In January 1786, he was admitted to the Connecticut bar. In October of 1791, he was elected to the Connecticut General Assembly from New Haven where he served continuously (the last three years as Speaker) until 1797, when he was elected to the Council. Daggett's tenure in the Council was marked, as was in fact his entire subsequent career, by those political principles which made him one of the prominent figures in the Federalist Party.
He retained his seat in the Council until his resignation in 1804. In 1805, he was again elected to the Assembly, serving until 1809, at which time he again became a member of the Council.
In June of 1811, he was appointed State's Attorney for New Haven County and in 1812 was a Presidential elector.
In May of 1813, Daggett was elected to the United States Senate as a Federalist where he pursued much the same course as the other New England Federalists as a defender of states' rights.
At the close of his senatorial term in 1819, he returned to New Haven and his law practice. In 1824, he was appointed an associate instructor in the Yale Law School and in 1826 as Kent Professor of Law, a post he held until 1848.
He also served as Associate Justice of the Superior Court of Connecticut from 1826 to 1832, when he was made Chief Justices of the Supreme Court of Errors, a position he held until 1834, when he reached the mandatory retirement age of seventy. He was also Mayor of the City of New Haven from 1828 to 1830.
On September 10, 1786, he married Wealthy Ann Munson, daughter of Dr. Eneas Munson of New Haven. Following her death on July 9, 1839, he married, May 4, 1840, Mary Lines, daughter of Capt. Major and Susanna (Mansfield) Lines.
David Daggett died on April 12, 1851, in his eighty-seventh year.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Law; Connecticut -- History; New Haven (Conn.); United States -- History -- 1783-1865; United States -- Politics and government; Educators; Lawyers; Politicians; Baldwin, Simeon, 1761-1851; Bishop, Abraham, 1763-1844; Bristol, William; Bronson, Isaac, 1760-1838; Calhoun, John C. (John Caldwell), 1782-1850; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Daggett, David, 1764-1851; Daggett, Leonard Augustus, 1790-1867; Denison, Charles, 1778-1825; Dwight, Susan Edwards, 1788-1839; Goodrich, Elizur, 1761-1849; Granger, Gideon, 1767-1822; Griswold, Roger, 1762-1812; Jenkins, Wealthy Ann Daggett, 1786-1860; King, Rufus, 1755-1827; Leffingwell, William, 1765-1834; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822; Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813; Smith, John Cotton, 1765-1845; Story, Joseph, 1779-1845; Trumbull, John, 1756-1843; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852; Webster, Noah, 1758-1843; Whitney, Eli, 1765-1825; Wirt, William, 1772-1834; Wolcott, Oliver, 1760-1833; Doggett family; Federal Party (Conn.); Federal Party (U.S.); Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, Series I
  - "A" - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbe, Shubael (1744-1804), 1790 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abel, Elijah (1738-1809), 1792 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Thomas, 1803 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, John (1763-1812), 1797-1802 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alvord, James C., 1839 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Joseph (1757-1837), 1816 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Astor, John Jacob (1763-1848), 1823, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Atwater, Jeremiah (1773-1858), 1816-1819 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Atwater, Lucius, 1817, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Atwater, Moses (1765-1847), 1803, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Austin, David (1759-1831), 1788 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Austin, Samuel, 1785-1786 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "B" - General (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Backus, Azel (1765-1816), 1807, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Backus, Joseph, 1804-1821 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Backus, Simon (1738-1823), 1821 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bacon, Asa (1771-1857), 1806, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bagot, Sir Charles (1781-1843), 1819 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Baker, N.H., 1819-1832 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baldwin, Henry (1780-1844), 1830, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman (1793-1863), 1819 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baldwon, Simeon (1761-1851), 1804-1819 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barbour, James (1775-1842), 1819-1826 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Barker, Samuel Still Augustus (1756-1819), 1802 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Barlow, Ruth (Baldwin) (1756-1818), 1816 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Barnes, Jonathan (1763-1829), 1786 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Barstow, Zedekiah Smith (1790-1873), 1845 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Beecher, Philemon, 1824-1825 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Beers, Isaac (1742-1813), 1794-1804 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Beers, Nathan (1753-1849), 1814-1815 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Beers, Seth Preston (1781-1868), 1818 (Box 1, Folder 31a)
  - Belden, Hezekian (1778-1849), 1817-1819 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Benedict, Thaddeus (1749-1799), 1797 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Benjamin, Park (1809-1864), 1838 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bennett, Joseph, 1825, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Benson, Egbert (1746-1833), 1807 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Betts, Thaddeus (1789-1840), 1833, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bibb, William W. (1780-1820), 1817-1818 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bidwell, Barnabes (1763-1833), 1787 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Binney, Horace (1780-1875), 1815 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bird, John (1768-1806), 1789-1799 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bishop, Abraham (1764-1844), 1787-1814 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bissell, Clark (1782-1857), 1833 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Blackman, Samuel C., 1803-1814 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Blake, George, 1821-1823, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bledsoe, Jesse (1776-1837), 1814 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bliss, George (1764-1830), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Boardman, Daniel (1757-1833), 1799 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Boardman, William Whiting (1794-1871), 1840-1841 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bostwick, Charles, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bradish, Luther (1783-1863), 1830 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bradley, Joseph, 1806-1807 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Bradley, Philip B. (1738-1821), 1798 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Brainard, Jermiah Gates (1759-1830), 1818-1819 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Brainerd, Jehu (1757-1815), 1783 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Bray, A., 1806, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Bray, O., 1801-1804, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Brinsmade, Daniel Nathaniel (1751-1826), 1789 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Bristol, William, 1800-1836 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bronson, Enos (1774-1823), 1801 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Bronson, Isaac (1760-1839), 1807-1819 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Brooms, Samuel (1735?-1810), 1805 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Brown, James (1766-1835), 1819 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Brown, William (1764-1803), 1797, 1800 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Buel, Abel (1772-1820), 1795 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Bull, Thomas, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Burrill, James (1772-1820), 1799-1820 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Bussey, Benjamin (1757-1842), 1801 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - C - General (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell (1782-1850), 1826-1836 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Carrington, Edward (1747-1795), 1791 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Champion, Epaphroditus (1756-1834), 1807-1813 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Channing, Henry (1760-1840), 1787-1790 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Chapman, Asa (1770-1825), 1810-1825 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Chipman, Daniel (1765-1850), 1821 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Church, Samuel (1765-1854), 1832 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Clark, Cyrus, 1800-1819 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Clay, Henry (1777-1852), 1825-1835 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Cleaveland, Moses (1754-1806), 1788, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Cogswell, Mason Fitch (1761-1830), 1821 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Coleman, William (1766-1829), 1809-1818 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Colt, Peter (1744-1824), 1800-1816 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Converse, Sherman (1790-1873), 1818-1822 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Coyle, John (& family), 1816-1829 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Cranch, William (1769-1855), 1807, 1818 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Crawford, William Harris (1772-1834), 1816-1832 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Crittenden, John Jordan (1787-1863), 1820, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - D - General (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Daggett, Abner (1755-1832), 1788-1822 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Daggett, Leonard Augustus (1790-1867), 1813-1816 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Daggett, Naphtali, 1799, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Daggett, Wealthy Ann (Munson) (1767-1839), 1814-1818 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Dallas, Alexander (1759-1817), 1816 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Dana, Samuel Whittlesey (1760-1830), 1805-1829 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Darling, Joseph (1759-1850), 1817 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Davenport, James (1758-1797), 1796 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Dawes, Thomas (1757-1825), 1787 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Day, Jeremiah (1773-1867), 1814, 1822 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Day, Thomas (1777-1855), 1818-1846 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - DeForest, David Curtis (1774-1825), 1819-1822 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - DeForest, John Hancock (1776-1839), 1806-1827 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Delaplaine, Joseph (1777-1824), 1818 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Denison, Charles (1778-1825), 1813-1819 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - DeSaussure, Henry William (1763-1839), 1804-1815 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Devotion, Ebenezer (1740-1829), 1789 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - DeWitt, Abraham V.H., 1792-1810 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Dudley, Josiah, 1804-1811 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Dunn, William Mckee (1814-1887), 1836, 1838 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Dutton, Matthew Rice (1783-1825), 1818 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Dwight, Sereno Edwards (1786-1850), 1814 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Dwight, Susan Edwards (Daggett) (1788-1839), 1804-1838 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Dwight, Theodore (1764-1846), 1802-1828 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Dwight, Timothy (1778-1844), 1818 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - E - General (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Edward, William (1755-1838), 1797-1802 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Edwards, Jonathan (1745-1801), 1795 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Edwards, Justin (1787-1853), 1831 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Edwards, Pierpont (1750-1826), 1788-1807 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Ellery, Christopher (1768-1840), 1789-1790 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Ellsworth, Henry Leavitt (1791-1858), 1826-1835 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Ellsworth, William Wolcott (1791-1868), 1826-1831 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Eppes, John Wayles (1773-1823), 1819 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Everett, Edward (1794-1865), 1836, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - F - General (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Fairchild, Robert (1775-1835), 1808 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Fisher, Alexander Metcalf (1794-1822), 1819 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Fobes, Peres (1742-1812), 1795-1799 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Foot, Samuel Augustus (1780-1846), 1833 (Box 4, Folder 127a)
  - Frelinghuysen, Theodore (1787-1861), 1834, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Freneau, Peter (1757-1813), 1793-1798 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - G - General (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Gaillard, John (1765-1826), 1819-1824 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Gales, Joseph (1786-1860), 1821, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Gilbert, Sylvester (1755-1846), 1799-1811 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Gillet, Canfield, 1813-1814 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Goddard, Calvin (1768-1842), 1799-1842 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Gold, Thomas Ruggles (1764-1827), 1812, 1816 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Goldsborough, Robert H. (1780-1836), 1821-1836 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Goodrich, Chauncey (1759-1815), 1800-1815 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Goodrich, Elizur (1761-1849), 1799-1828 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Goodwin, George (1757-1844), 1801-1829 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Gore, Christopher (1758-1827), 1792, 1818 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Gould, James, 1795-1820 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Gould, Orchard, 1786-1812 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Granger, Gideon (1767-1822), 1795-1814 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Green, Ashbel (1762-1848), 1819 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Greenleaf, Simon (1783-1853), 1834 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Grennell, George (1786-1877), 1835-1836 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Griswold, Charles, 1816, 1817 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Griswold, George (1777-1859), 1813-1831 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Griswold, Roger (1762-1812), 1794-1812 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Griswold, Stanley (1763-1815), 1797, 1815 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - H - General (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Hagner, Peter (1772-1850), 1811, 1816 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Hale, David (1791-1849), 1823 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Hare, Robert (1781-1858), 1817 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Harper, Robert Goodloe (1765-1825), 1817-1820 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Hart, Elisha, 1803, 1805 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Hart, William (1746-1817), 1792-1810 (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Hatch, Moses (1780-1820), 1802-1820 (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Hawes, Joel (1789-1867), 1828, undated (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Helms, Samuel, 1790-1805 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Hillhouse, James (1754-1832), 1791-1817 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Hillhouse, William (1757-1833), 1807-1816 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Hitchcock, Samuel Johnson (1786-1845), 1818, 1833 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Hoffman, David (1784-1854), 1823-1826 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Hoffman, Joseph Ogden, 1799-1815 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Holmes, Abiel (1763-1837), 1783-1798 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Hopkins, Samuel Miles (1772-1837), 1791-1835 (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - Hosmer, Stephen Titus (1763-1834), 1798-1832 (Box 6, Folder 169)
  - Howe, Hezekiah (1775-1838), 1814-1815 (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - Hubbard, Thomas 1776-1838), 1819 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - Hull, Isaac (1773-1843), 1814-1818 (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Humphreys, David (1752-1818), 1812-1816 (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Humphreys, John (1774-1826), 1803, 1807 (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - Huntington, Ebenezer (1754-1834), 1803-1804 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Huntington, Jabez Williams (1788-1847), 1829-1841 (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - Huntington, Samuel (1731-1796), 1793-1794 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - I - General (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Ingersoll, Jared (1749-1822), 1787 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - Ingersoll, Jonathan (1747-1823), 1795-1819 (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Ingersoll, Joseph Reed (1786-1868), 1826 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Isaacs, Ralph (1741-1799), 1798 (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - Isham, Jirah (1778-1842), 1798-1812 (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - J - General (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Jenkins, Wealthy Ann (Daggett) (1796-1860), 1813-1845 (Box 6, Folder 185-186)
  - Jocelin, Samuel R. (17? -1817), 1803-1812 (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - Jocelyn, Nathaniel (1796-1881), 1828 (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - Johnson, Samuel William (1761-1846), 1794-1827 (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Judd, William, 1790, 1792 (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - K - General (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Kent, James (1763-1847), 1822-1832 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - King, Rufus (1755-1827), 1814-1822 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Kingsley, James Luce (1778-1852), 1821, 1836 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Kirby, Ephraim (1757-1804), 1793 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - L - General (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Lanman, James (1767-1841), 1814 (Box 7, Folder 197)
  - Law, John (1796-1873), 1814-1819 (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - Law, Lyman (1770-1842), 1799-1824 (Box 7, Folder 199)
  - Lee, Charles (1758-1815), 1807 (Box 7, Folder 200)
  - Leffingwell, Christopher, 1788-1802 (Box 7, Folder 201)
  - Leffingwell, William (1765-1834), 1786-1833 (Box 7, Folder 202)
  - Leonard, Elijah (1760-1834), 1781-1814 (Box 7, Folder 203)
  - Lewis, Eleanor P. Custis (1779-1852), 1818 (Box 7, Folder 204)
  - Lewis, Morgan (1754-1844), 1809 (Box 7, Folder 205)
  - Livingston, [Henry] Brockholst (1757-1823), 1813-1819 (Box 7, Folder 206)
  - Lowndes, William (1782-1822), 1818-1820 (Box 7, Folder 207)
  - Lyman, Joseph, 1829-1835 (Box 7, Folder 208)
  - Lyon, William (1748-1830), 1814-1818 (Box 7, Folder 209)
  - M - General (Box 7, Folder 210)
  - McKenney, Thomas Lorraine (1785-1859), 1814 (Box 7, Folder 211)
  - Macon, Nathaniel (1747-1837), 1818, 1821 (Box 7, Folder 212)
  - Madison, James (1751-1836), 1812 (Box 7, Folder 212a)
  - Mansfield, Jared (1759-1830), 1804-1819 (Box 7, Folder 213)
  - Marshall, John (1755-1835), 1807 (Box 7, Folder 214)
  - Mason, Jeremiah (1768-1848), 1817-1823 (Box 7, Folder 215)
  - May, Elisha, 1786-1787 (Box 7, Folder 216)
  - Meigs, Josiah (1757-1822), 1816-1822 (Box 7, Folder 217)
  - Meigs, Return Jonathan (1764-1825), 1818 (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Mellen, Prentiss (1764-1840), 1820-1838 (Box 7, Folder 219)
  - Miller, Asher (1753-1821), 1788 (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Mills, Isaac (1767-1843), 1787-1818 (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Mitchell, Justus, 1801-1803 (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Mitchell, Stephen Mix (1743-1835), 1813-1814 (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Mitchell, Walter (1777-1849), 1804-1835 (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Monroe, James (1758-1831), 1814, 1816 (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - Monson, Aeneas [Eneas] (1763-1852), 1787-1822 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - Morgan, John (1753-1842), 1795-1811 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Morse, Jedidah (1761-1826), 1783-1819 (Box 8, Folder 228)
  - Morse, Samuel Finley Breese (1791-1872), 1823 (Box 8, Folder 229)
  - Mosely, Jonathan Ogden (1762-1838), 1798-1821 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Munson, Eneas (1734-1826), 1791-1818 (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Munson, Israel (1767-1844), 1795-1828 (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - N - General (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - O - General (Box 8, Folder 234)
  - Ogden, Aaron (1756-1839), 1789 (Box 8, Folder 235)
  - P - General (Box 8, Folder 236)
  - Parker, Isaac (1768-1830), 1815 (Box 8, Folder 237)
  - Perkins, Enoch (1760-1828), 1806-1814 (Box 8, Folder 238)
  - Peters, John Thompson (1765-1834), 1797-1826 (Box 8, Folder 239)
  - Phelps, Elisha, 1818 (Box 8, Folder 240)
  - Pickering, Octavius, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 241)
  - Pickering, Timothy (1745-1829), 1816 (Box 8, Folder 242)
  - Pierpont, [Henry?] B., 1801-1802 (Box 8, Folder 243)
  - Pinckney, Thomas (1750-1828), 1818 (Box 8, Folder 244)
  - Pinkney, William (1764-1822), 1821-1822 (Box 8, Folder 245)
  - Pitkin, Timothy (1766-1847), 1810-1815 (Box 8, Folder 246)
  - Pitkin, William (1725-1789), 1786 (Box 8, Folder 247)
  - Pond, Enoch (1791-1882), 1825 (Box 8, Folder 248)
  - Pope, Charles, M., 1829 (Box 8, Folder 249)
  - Pope, Nathaniel (1784-1850), 1818 (Box 8, Folder 250)
  - Porter, Jonathan Edwards (1768-1821), 1817 (Box 8, Folder 251)
  - Porter, Joshua (1730-1825), 1811 (Box 8, Folder 252)
  - Quincy, Josiah (1772-1864), 1813-1832 (Box 8, Folder 253)
  - R - General (Box 9, Folder 254)
  - Radcliffe, Peter W. (1774-1840), 1807-1810 (Box 9, Folder 255)
  - Rawle, William (1759-1836), 1814, 1817 (Box 9, Folder 256)
  - Reeve, Tapping (1744-1823), 1792-1818 (Box 9, Folder 257)
  - Richards, Guy (1747-1825), 1814 (Box 9, Folder 258)
  - Robbins, Asher (1761-1845), 1791, 1836 (Box 9, Folder 259)
  - Rogers, Ammi (1770-1852), 1808-1812 (Box 9, Folder 260)
  - Root, Jesse (1736-1822), 1798 (Box 9, Folder 261)
  - Rowland, Samuel, 1800-1825 (Box 9, Folder 262)
  - Ruggles, Benjamin (1783-1857), 1820-1825 (Box 9, Folder 263)
  - Rush, Benjamin (1745-1813), 1794 (Box 9, Folder 264)
  - Rush, Charles (1780-1859), 1827 (Box 9, Folder 265)
  - S - General (Box 9, Folder 266)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett (1783-1845), 1818-1819 (Box 9, Folder 267)
  - Seaton, William Winston (1785-1866), 1814 (Box 9, Folder 268)
  - Sedgwick, Theodore (1746-1813), 1799 (Box 9, Folder 269)
  - Sergeant, John (1779-1852), 1821 (Box 9, Folder 270)
  - Seybert, Adam (1773-1825), 1817 (Box 9, Folder 271)
  - Seymour, Horatio (1778-1857), 1806 (Box 9, Folder 272)
  - Seymour, Moses (1742-1826), 1796 (Box 9, Folder 273)
  - Seymour, Thomas Youngs (1757-1811), 1794-1803 (Box 9, Folder 274)
  - Sheffield, Joseph Earl (1793-1882), 1838-1842 (Box 9, Folder 275)
  - Sherman, Roger (1768-1856), 1811 (Box 9, Folder 276)
  - Sherman, Roger Minott (1773-1844), 1798-1826 (Box 9, Folder 277)
  - Silliman, Benjamin (1779-1864), 1803-1842 (Box 9, Folder 278)
  - Skinner, Roger Sherman (1795-1838), 1819, 1829 (Box 9, Folder 279)